<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Vinay Panchal</title>
    <link href="https://vinaypanchal.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://vinaypanchal.com" />
    <updated>2022-01-30T01:08:57+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Vinay Panchal</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://vinaypanchal.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Savings vs Investments</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vinay Panchal</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vinaypanchal.com/savings-vs-investment.html"/>
        <id>https://vinaypanchal.com/savings-vs-investment.html</id>
            <category term="Research"/>

        <updated>2022-01-30T01:08:57+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/paisa.jpg" alt="Savings vs Investment" />
                    Hello everyone, as every other blog even this will include stuff in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/paisa.jpg" alt="Savings vs Investment" />
                <p>Hello everyone, as every other blog even this will include stuff in a more simple and understandable perspective using least amount of words, so you might need to read again if you too a slow grasper and lazy person like me.</p>
<p>So before starting with the whole Savings vs Investments thing what is the core ideology that differentiates one from another, Let's look at some money related concepts about how it came into existence in the first place and what is money anyways.</p>
<h2>History of exchange</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/barter.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/barter-xs.png 300w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/barter-sm.png 480w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/barter-md.png 768w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/barter-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="1500" height="1088"></figure>
<blockquote>
<p>Not everyone is good at everything,</p>
<p>But everyone is good at something</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So in order to survive we need a lots of things we ain't good at. And this lead to the idea of exchanging stuff (and not donating because everyone is greedy). Hence Barter system was developed. You give something the other person needs and get something you need in return... Win-Win situation. Both parties benefited. it can be in terms of goods(bananas, chocolates) or also in terms of service(traveling, cleaning).</p>
<p>It's all great and smooth if two people have opposite stuff to exchange. But it's really difficult to exchange when both people have the same stuff. I hope you know what i mean, Like who gives whom what? And what if first person has something the second person wants but the second person doesn't have something the first person wants.</p>
<p>Let's see a table to understand this problem</p>
<table style="border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; height: 250px;" border="1">
<tbody>
<tr style="height: 50px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">People</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Stuff they have</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Stuff they need </td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">A</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Apples</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">iPhone</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">B</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Bananas</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Apples</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">C</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Chocolates</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Bananas</td>
</tr>
<tr style="height: 50px;">
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">D</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">iPhone</td>
<td style="width: 33.3333%; height: 50px;">Chocolates</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>So in order for "A" to get iPhone</p>
<ol>
<li>"A" gives Apples to "B" and gets Bananas in return.</li>
<li>"A" takes those Bananas and gives it to "C" and gets Chocolates in return.</li>
<li>"A" takes those Chocolates and gives it to "D" to finally get iPhone.</li>
</ol>
<p>Hectic right? so people thought what if we use something for exchange that everyone has but also has value to it so no one uses it in vain.</p>
<p>And that's how concept of money was born. Some common token to exchange in order to get goods or services you want. It wasn't cash or bitcoins all the time, it started with declaring beads as common mode of exchange then shifted to coins and then paper. While now moving towards digital, The idea of having a common exchange token remains the same.</p>
<h2>Liquidity</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/liquidity.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/liquidity-xs.png 300w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/liquidity-sm.png 480w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/liquidity-md.png 768w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/liquidity-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="1500" height="700"></figure>
<p>Liquid is something that takes shape of whatever you put it into. Like water takes shape of a bottle when poured into one or even a dish.</p>
<p>Similarly Money is said to be liquid because when exchanged with anything it takes the value of that thing. We can buy Donut and a rocket with the same money. Of course the amount will differ a lot but it's money in both cases unlike Barter system.</p>
<p>The term Liquidity refers to how fast you can get your money into a usable state. It will get more clear in the end of the blog.</p>
<h2>Value of money</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/cash.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/cash-xs.png 300w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/cash-sm.png 480w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/cash-md.png 768w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/cash-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="548" height="251"></figure>
<p>Now that we sure about money being in the center of exchange, Let's talk about it's value of exchange.</p>
<p>There's this concept called Inflation. Which is a really complex process. Will see it in later blogs, but right now just remember that "Value of Money Degrades with Time". If you can buy a pencil for 10 Rupees today, let's suppose it will be 11 Rupees after a year, So the inflation is 0.1</p>
<pre class="formulax"><strong>Inflation = (CPI <sub>x+1</sub> – CPI <sub>x</sub>) / CPI <sub>x</sub></strong><br><br>Where,<br><strong>CPI <sub>x+1</sub></strong>: CPI of Current Year<br><strong>CPI <sub>x</sub></strong>: CPI of Previous Year</pre>
<h2>Zero Cashflow</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/savings.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/savings-xs.jpg 300w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/savings-sm.jpg 480w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/savings-md.jpg 768w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/savings-lg.jpg 1024w"  alt="" width="474" height="316"></figure>
<p> </p>
<p>Well technically,</p>
<pre>Savings = Income – (Consumption + Taxes)</pre>
<p>This is how you calculate the amount of savings in your pocket or piggy bank. But what is saving anyways? What happens to that saved money?</p>
<p>The reason for saving can be anything,</p>
<ul>
<li>Education</li>
<li>Retirement</li>
<li>Emergency</li>
<li>Medical expense</li>
<li>Emergency medical Expense</li>
<li>Marriage</li>
<li>Emergency Marriage</li>
</ul>
<p>The point is list may go increasing. But the value of the money to fulfill the list will keep decreasing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Saving money is allowing money to decay in your pocket,</p>
<p>While getting the liquidity to use it anytime you wish,</p>
<p>With least risk of loosing.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2>Dealing Mangoes</h2>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/mango.png" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" srcset="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/mango-xs.png 300w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/mango-sm.png 480w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/mango-md.png 768w ,https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/3/responsive/mango-lg.png 1024w"  alt="" width="869" height="683"></figure>
<p>So we know that money won't grow on it's own. We need to make it. So how do we do that now?</p>
<p>Remember in the beginning we talked about money being exchanged with any stuff we need? Well let's exchange it something we don't need at all, but something that will increase in value over the time. Let's see this with an example.</p>
<p>Let's buy 1 Kg of raw mangoes for 100 Rupees this summer. And then make pickles from those. When the winter comes, sell the pickle for 500 Rupees per Kg.</p>
<p>Notice what we did in the above scenario. We used the increasing value of Mangoes to leverage our money returns. That's what we call an investment. There's a risk though of mangoes going stale. And also a chance of no one buying your mangoes. Even if someone buys it, You need to wait until winter to sell. So the liquidity is low because you can't use those mangoes in your house midway as a token of exchange instead of money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is exchanging money with something that has increasing value over the period of time,</p>
<p>While not having enough Liquidity,</p>
<p>And that too with high risk.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thank You for reading, Do let me know about improvements, corrections and new ideas for further blogs.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Simple Search Bot in Python</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vinay Panchal</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vinaypanchal.com/simple-search-bot-in-python.html"/>
        <id>https://vinaypanchal.com/simple-search-bot-in-python.html</id>
            <category term="Coding"/>

        <updated>2021-11-29T21:52:09+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/2/download.jpg" alt="" />
                    Greetings!!! In this blog we will see how to make a Bot&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/2/download.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>Greetings!!!</p>
<p>In this blog we will see how to make a Bot in python which will search everything you copy to clipboard. Source code at the end of blog.</p>
<p>Past Covid-19 all examinations are conducted online and we all know why study if we can search everything on the internet. Particularly my university asked us to attempt exam through google form. So we had to follow a sequence of steps to search each question on the internet and get the solution.</p>
<ul>
<li>Select the question and Hit Ctrl + C on the keyboard</li>
<li>Open browser</li>
<li>Visit each MCQ website where solutions can be available</li>
<li>Search for solutions on all sites</li>
</ul>
<p>This steps had to be repeated for each and every question. Which felt hectic after few tests. So i wrote this bot which allowed me to perform just first step and rest were taken care by the bot.</p>
<p>Enough ChitChat! Let's start with the actual code.</p>
<p>First part will be importing the packages we will be needing to make this work.</p>
<pre>from pynput import keyboard<br>import time<br>import clipboard<br>import webbrowser<br>import pip</pre>
<p>Now you will be thinking...</p>
<p>We imported everything but didn't install any package in our environment. Since this blog is all about automating steps we will be automating this part too. How? just copy paste this next block of code and run</p>
<pre>def install(package):
    if hasattr(pip, 'main'):
        pip.main(['install', package])
    else:
        pip._internal.main(['install', package])


if __name__ == '__main__':
    install('pynput')
    install('clipboard')
    install('webbrowser')</pre>
<p>Now that we have all setup we can go dive into the main logic. We will create a text file and list down all the sites on which we want to search for the solutions and name the file "sites.txt". Here is my list for reference.</p>
<pre>sanfoundry.com
examradar.com
examveda.com
coursehero.com
careerride.com
tuteehub.com
quizelet.com
brainscape.com
compsciedu.com
ciscopress.com
gkseries.com
engineeringinterviewquestions.com
mcqslearns.com
texalab.com
brainly.in
educationforever.in
lecturenotes.in
pinoybix.org
calculator.in</pre>
<p>Now we will ask for consent on which search engine to choose</p>
<p>The one which keeps privacy safe - DuckDuckGo</p>
<p>Or the one with plays with our privacy who's name shall not be taken (Google) </p>
<pre>print("WHICH SEARCH ENGINE DO YOU USE?")
print("ENTER '0' FOR DUCK DUCK GO ")
print("OR ANY OTHER NUMBER FOR GOOGLE")
bchoice = int(input("BE QUICK \n"))

if bchoice == 0:
    print("NOICE!!! SMORT!!! TOIT!!! KEEP USING DUCKDUCKGO")
else:
    print("LEVEL UP DUDE AND START USING DUCK DUCK GO")
    time.sleep(3)
    print("")
    print("")
    print("ANYWAYS")

print("")
print("")
print("PORTAL STARTED")
print("now select any text and press control plus C ")
print("")</pre>
<p>Let's create a funtion to use this all info and do actual work. we will see each task in function one by one. Start by saving clipboard string into a variable</p>
<pre>text = clipboard.paste()</pre>
<p>A query needs to be created so that we can search for it on any search engine. And that will be done by combining our text to be searched and the sites list. One more thing we cannot enter empty spaces in URL so we will replace them all with "+" symbol.</p>
<pre>query = text + sites
query = query.replace(" ", "+")
</pre>
<p>Compose final URL to be searched for based on the search engine choice and save it in a variable.</p>
<pre>if bchoice == 0:
    openbrow = "https://duckduckgo.com/?q=" + query
else:
    openbrow = "https://www.google.com/search?q=" + query</pre>
<p>Now we can open web browser and enter the URL using "open" method on "webbrowser" but new window for every question will be mess so we keep the new attribute as "new=2" and we also want to keep that tab in focus so "autoraise=True"</p>
<pre>webbrowser.open(openbrow, new=2, autoraise=True)</pre>
<p>The final funtion will look as following</p>
<pre>def function_1():
    text = clipboard.paste()
    print(text)

    query = text + sites
    query = query.replace(" ", "+")

    if bchoice == 0:
        openbrow = "https://duckduckgo.com/?q=" + query
    else:
        openbrow = "https://www.google.com/search?q=" + query

    webbrowser.open(openbrow, new=2, autoraise=True)</pre>
<p>Only thing left is to trigger this funtion when someone presses Ctrl key and C key at once. That's when a text is coppied into the clipboard. </p>
<pre>with keyboard.GlobalHotKeys({
    '&lt;ctrl&gt;+c': function_1}) as h:
    h.join()</pre>
<p>DONE!!! </p>
<p>Now just run the file and you will be good to go.</p>
<p>Source code of this entire bot can be found at <a href="https://github.com/vinaynpp/searchbot" title="Github link" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://github.com/vinaynpp/searchbot</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>High School Research</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vinay Panchal</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vinaypanchal.com/high-school-research.html"/>
        <id>https://vinaypanchal.com/high-school-research.html</id>
            <category term="Research"/>

        <updated>2021-11-29T18:46:32+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/1/CAT-MONKEY-1.jpg" alt="" />
                     I was an average student in high school but my academic&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://vinaypanchal.com/media/posts/1/CAT-MONKEY-1.jpg" alt="" />
                <div class="separator" data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><a data-original-attrs="{&quot;data-original-href&quot;:&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AyrRq3NW1xA/WtMS3HbOp7I/AAAAAAAAABM/aVAtiz5QmcQhRwO7TrJXOMYRb8FMzvphwCLcBGAs/s1600/SCHOOL-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/9202629767217652780/6165044741028720531"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AyrRq3NW1xA/WtMS3HbOp7I/AAAAAAAAABM/aVAtiz5QmcQhRwO7TrJXOMYRb8FMzvphwCLcBGAs/s400/SCHOOL-1.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  width="400" height="282" border="0" data-original-height="1132" data-original-width="1600"></a></div>
<p><br><br></p>
<div> I was an average student in high school but my academic performance was degrading as I moved on to higher grades. I didn't use to get good marks in history but scored well in science and mathematics. So I approached my school teacher for the solution. Her solution changed my approach towards studies. </div>
<div> </div>
<div>She asked me to change the way of learning. She said, "IF YOU ARE BAD AT ANYTHING CO-RELATE IT WITH SOMETHiNG YOU ARE GOOD AT". So I tried to do it and even my grades improved after that. I started reading the history of inventions and discoveries. That was the moment I realized that one cannot be a good scientist if he is not preeminent. I would like to share one of such scenarios.</div>
<div> </div>
<h2 data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}">Theory of light </h2>
<div>
<div class="separator" data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><a data-original-attrs="{&quot;data-original-href&quot;:&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-l4o8RhG3zGg/WtBobpaQDoI/AAAAAAAAAAg/8aqHaSWt7tYno9mtVHV0NNg-EgiX1yC4QCLcBGAs/s1600/-untitled-.gif&quot;,&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/9202629767217652780/6165044741028720531"><img loading="lazy" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-l4o8RhG3zGg/WtBobpaQDoI/AAAAAAAAAAg/8aqHaSWt7tYno9mtVHV0NNg-EgiX1yC4QCLcBGAs/s400/-untitled-.gif" data-is-external-image="true"  width="400" height="225" border="0" data-original-height="720" data-original-width="1280"></a></div>
<br>We know corpuscular theory by Newton in 1672 while it was already stated by Descartes in 1637. Newton just copied the theory of Descartes and renamed it as Newton's corpuscular theory of light</div>
<div>We all know that light exhibits wave-like properties. Which was then stated by Huygens in 1678 which was contravening Newtons' theory. JUST BECAUSE OF NEWTON'S PRESTIGE AND POPULARITY, HIS THEORY WAS PREDOMINANT OVER HUYGENS'. James Clerk Maxwell in1864 modified Huygens' theory and stated light as an electromagnetic wave and explained interference and diffraction which was already studied by Thomas Young in 1803.<br><br></div>
<div> </div>
<h4 data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}">A folktale of two cats</h4>
<div data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}">
<div class="separator" data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><a data-original-attrs="{&quot;data-original-href&quot;:&quot;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gBvOoUmSEw0/WtBqay-V8iI/AAAAAAAAAAs/8Y8cAL9ZFYIuPlEqG-5Zdvw2adR71taggCLcBGAs/s1600/CAT%2BMONKEY-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/9202629767217652780/6165044741028720531"><img loading="lazy" src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gBvOoUmSEw0/WtBqay-V8iI/AAAAAAAAAAs/8Y8cAL9ZFYIuPlEqG-5Zdvw2adR71taggCLcBGAs/s400/CAT%2BMONKEY-1.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  width="400" height="282" border="0" data-original-height="1132" data-original-width="1600"></a></div>
<br>Once upon a time, there were two cats fighting for a piece of bread. A monkey saw this from a distance. Approaches the cats and said that he can solve the dispute. Cats agreed, monkey ate the whole bread and ran away.<br>The story repeated.<br>People were busy with Newton and Huygens,<br>Einstein showed up with Dual Nature.<br>
<div class="separator" data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><a data-original-attrs="{&quot;data-original-href&quot;:&quot;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mtpJMewDRAI/WtBqot6htEI/AAAAAAAAAAw/44vfvRr7afMW0xEOf89PnqF7Sey9-75UQCLcBGAs/s1600/DUAL%2BNATURE-1.jpg&quot;,&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/9202629767217652780/6165044741028720531"><img loading="lazy" src="https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-mtpJMewDRAI/WtBqot6htEI/AAAAAAAAAAw/44vfvRr7afMW0xEOf89PnqF7Sey9-75UQCLcBGAs/s400/DUAL%2BNATURE-1.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  width="400" height="282" border="0" data-original-height="1132" data-original-width="1600"></a></div>
</div>
<h4 data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"> </h4>
<h4 data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}">Twitter Relations.</h4>
<div data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><br>Twitter was recently founded in 2006 but the concept was already used by the researchers.<br>One person works hard and posts original content while others just retweet and try to get the credit. The same way one inventor or discoverer works hard while others take their credit.<br>Speak of taking credits and Tesla arrives.</div>
<h4 data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"> </h4>
<div>
<div class="separator" data-original-attrs="{&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}"><a data-original-attrs="{&quot;data-original-href&quot;:&quot;https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2OOTKQhG6Co/WtBrFqLykPI/AAAAAAAAAA4/4TROilCPSS8qLw302Qqpsmqk_tJLTOe8gCLcBGAs/s1600/Nikola%2BTesla%2B3D.jpg&quot;,&quot;style&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" href="https://draft.blogger.com/u/1/blog/post/edit/9202629767217652780/6165044741028720531"><img loading="lazy" src="https://4.bp.blogspot.com/-2OOTKQhG6Co/WtBrFqLykPI/AAAAAAAAAA4/4TROilCPSS8qLw302Qqpsmqk_tJLTOe8gCLcBGAs/s400/Nikola%2BTesla%2B3D.jpg" data-is-external-image="true"  width="307" height="400" border="0" data-original-height="1600" data-original-width="1234"></a></div>
</div>
<div> </div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
